Guide to the Duncan Foley Papers, 1965-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Duncan Foley papers 1965-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Foley, Duncan K.
16.5 Linear Feet 12375 Items
Economist and professor at the New School for Social Research.
Collection contains writings and research, correspondence, name files, teaching and academic materials, and some personal and creative work by Foley. Common subjects include Marxism and monetary theory, statistical methodology, and political economy. This material has been minimally processed and may include restricted items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted. Referee reports are restricted, requiring written permission from Duncan Foley to access, for ten years from date of creation. Personnel evaluations (tenure reviews, etc) are restricted, requiring written permission from Duncan Foley to access, for 25 years from date of creation.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Duncan Foley Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Biographical Note
Duncan K. Foley graduated from Swarthmore College with a B.A. in Mathematics in 1964, and received the Ph.D. in Economics from Yale University in 1966. He has taught at M.I.T., Stanford, Barnard College of Columbia University, and since 1999 has been Leo Model Professor at the Economics Department of the New School for Social Research. He is an External Professor at the Santa Fe Institute.
He has published in the fields of Public Finance, Macroeconomics, Money, Marxist Economic Theory, Economic Dynamics, Neo-Ricardian Economics, Growth Theory, and Complex Systems Theory and Economics.
Foley's recent work includes studies of the relation of statistical mechanics and thermodynamics to economics, global warming policy, complexity theory and Classical political economy ("Unholy Trinity: Labor, Capital and Land in the New Economy", Routledge, 2003), work on the foundations of statistical method, and Marx's theory of money. He published a book on the history of political economy and economics, "Adam's Fallacy: A Guide to Economic Theology", in 2006.
Excerpted from Foley's biography from the Institute for New Economic Thinking.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Foley, Duncan K.
Stanford University. Dept. of Economics
Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dept. of Economics
Finance, public
Stabilization funds
Macroeconomics
Economics -- money
Marxian economics
Keynesian economics
Economics -- Study and teaching
Economists
Contents of Collection
- Writings and Research, 1965-1999, (5 boxes)
  Series includes Foley's research and writings files, including his notes and research on various economic subjects including Marxism, money and monetary policy, economic stabilization, statistical equality, Keynesian economics, complexity theory, and macroeconomics. Series contains drafts and revisions of Foley's many articles, book reviews, and drafts and materials from his own books. Original folders have been maintained. Items are sorted and grouped in loose alphabetical order. Note that folders have been arranged by Foley's own naming scheme, which sometimes results in his articles being sorted by co-author rather than by topic.
  - A-E (Box 1)
  - E-J (Box 2)
  - J-M (Box 3)
  - M-P (Box 4)
  - P-Z (Box 5)
- Name File, (1 box)
  Correspondence, collaborations, research, and other materials arranged by Foley using the author or subject's name.
  - A-Z (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1960s-1998, (3 boxes)
  Correspondence files kept by Foley, arranged in a loose chronological order. This series has not been arranged; items are in their original order within each folder.
  - Correspondence, 1960s-1977 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1995 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 9)
- Personal and Miscellany, (1 box)
  Series includes drafts of scripts and plays, written by Foley, as well as some amateur radio materials. Also includes Foley's day planners from the 1960s and 1970s.
  - Scripts and drafts, notes, etc. (Box 9)
  - Calendar diaries, 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
- Writings by Others, (3 boxes)
  Unsorted articles and drafts by other economists, including co-collaborators.
  - Writings by others, unsorted (Box 9)
  - Writings by others, unsorted (Box 10)
  - Writings by others, unsorted (Box 12)
- Teaching Files, 1970s-2000s, (1 box)
  Lecture notes, class plans, and other materials related to Foley's teaching career. This series has not been arranged; items are in their original order within each folder.
  - Teaching files, unsorted (Box 10)
- Economics Dept. Files, 1970s-1990s, (1 box)
  Tenure reviews, referee reports, references and recommendation letters, grant applications, and other departmental work. This series has not been arranged; items are in their original order within each folder.
  - Economics Dept. files, unsorted (Box 11)